[child 1] Ollie. Ada.
Mom's coming.
[children laughing]
[child 1] Come on. this way.
[child 2 coughs]
[coughing. choking]
[baby screaming]
[parent] Girls!
[child 1] Mom!
Rose!
[Rose] Mom. where are you?
[child 3] Mommy!
[Rose] Help us! Mom!
[gasping]
- [wind howling]
- [gasping]
[gasps]
[breathes shakily]
[inhales. exhales deeply]
[sighs]
[parent] Dear Lord.
we ask that you keep the storms at bay.
Calm the dust.
We thank you for bringing Henry this job.
Preserve those who travel.
Bring Henry in safety
to his journey's end.
Let him earn enough to finish our home.
Plant a crop.
Help me.
Help me to see the gifts you've given me
rather than the things you've taken away.
Help me to keep
Rose and Ollie healthy and safe.
Don't let them fall ill
like the other children.
Rose. toss down some hay. sweetheart.
Just a little.
We have to make it last.
Bruise me. bloody me.
if it means you
won't touch a hair on their heads.
Please kiss Ada for me.
Promise her that I will
fend off my human proneness
for evil so that we can be together again.
All of us.
[parent] And when I lie awake tonight.
banish worry from my heart.
Reward me with peaceful black sleep.
Amen.
[sighs] I asked your daddy to patch this.
There's just never enough time.
You think he'll see Philadelphia?
No. it's too far east.
Well. I wanna see it.
Hmm.
[Rose] I wanna see what it's like.
Maybe next summer.
If the crops come in.
Lock this behind me.
[Rose] Follow my finger as I read. okay?
"The Grey Man locked his lovely wife
and five children in the bedroom.
then gathered embers from the fire.
He aimed to burn the six angels up.
but fate had one more victim in mind.
As the flames leaped higher.
the Grey Man
realized his shirt was caught.
It was no use.
The flames consumed him.
Now. during a dust storm.
the Grey Man's ashes blow together.
He walks the night.
If you don't wear your mask.
you'll breathe him in.
and he'll make you do terrible things."
[breathing heavily]
[parent sighs]
[Henry] You could come with me.
[sighs]
I won't put them in a tent.
lose what little we have.
And I won't leave her out there.
Alone.
[gulps]
Girl...
[gasps]
[knocking]
[neighbor] So. how'd
Henry get off last week?
- Well...
- Yeah?
There were quite a few heading out.
Last man standing.
- [neighbor] Oh. I'm so sorry.
- That's all right.
Just... It's hard to keep up with.
[chuckles]
[coughing]
He's been at that all night.
Is it that cold that was going around?
It started out like that.
but it's just... it's just gotten worse.
- It's pneumonia. Dr. Cox says.
- [child coughs]
[neighbor] Oh. it's not catching.
Doctor says it's
just too much dust in the air.
What are we meant to do about that?
It's a battle.
- [wind howling]
- [gasping]
[gasps]
[panting]
[sighs]
[inhales deeply]
[parent] Thomas has been poorly.
[churchgoer 1] Well. they should go see
that faith healer over in Guymon.
He pulled the arthritis
right out of an old man's fingers.
Bones just straightened right out.
[chuckles]
It's good you brought the girls. Margaret.
Why is that?
I guess you haven't heard about Calabash.
The daddy said the door was locked.
But the drifter
got into the house somehow.
Ransacked the pantry.
They found him
eating crackers over the baby.
No. Birdie.
he'd already finished the crackers.
He was just looking at the baby.
[stammers] He must have been hungry.
[churchgoer 1] Hunger don't explain
staring at a baby like that.
[Birdie] Just staring.
[churchgoer 1] And it certainly don't
explain what he did after.
[smacks lips] He tied the daddy up
and made him watch
while he killed the mama and the kids.
[Birdie] Gutted like hogs.
Can't keep up with chores as it is.
How am I supposed
to watch out for fiends too?
You keep your guard up.
Always.
[churchgoer 2] Did they ever catch him?
The drifter.
No. not yet.
And I can't figure it.
Nobody saw him leave.
It's like he just melted into the dust.
- [door slams]
- [all gasp]
[wind howling]
[churchgoer 3] Oh. sweet Jesus.
[Margaret] Goodness. [sighs]
- You're not leaving today.
- [horse whinnies]
[neighbor] Trying to.
[Margaret] The wind is terrible.
There must be a storm coming.
[neighbor] There's always a storm coming.
But people die in them and
you'll be exposed on that cart. Esther.
Unprotected.
All you need to do is make sure
Thomas and Jacob stay inside.
Clean. Seal the house.
[sighs] Even so.
it seeps through everything.
Keep finding it in the oddest places.
[breathes shakily]
I had a dream last night that. um...
He would not stop coughing.
[Thomas coughing]
I took a handkerchief.
and I stuffed it in his mouth.
Over and over and over.
[Thomas coughs]
[sniffles]
Sorry. [cries]
I just got to get my boys outta here.
[Thomas coughing]
[horse whinnies]
[Jacob] Whoa. Easy. Easy.
[rattling]
[Margaret. Rose panting]
[rumbling]
[panting]
[squeaking]
[Margaret] Girls. grab the twine
or you'll get lost in the dust!
[Rose] Where's Ollie?
I can't see her.
- [breathes heavily]
- [wind howling]
[breathing heavily]
[door slams]
[breathing shakily]
[Margaret] What man?
Stay here.
[Rose] Mom. don't go out there.
[wind howling]
[Margaret panting]
[crash]
The Grey Man?
You scared her with this. Rose.
Didn't I tell you to get rid of this?
Yeah.
This should help with the dust. okay?
[Rose] What about that man?
That drifter that disappeared.
There isn't anyone out there.
Understand?
I'm taking this.
[sighs]
[creaking]
Will you tell us about the wheat?
[sighs]
The first year we planted.
it just took hold.
When the wind blew.
the weeds would wave like the ocean.
And one day. we played hide-and-seek
in the tall grass for hours.
Come on.
Hurry up. [laughs]
[Margaret] You could hide
inches away. and I couldn't see you.
[laughing]
[Margaret] But I could
always hear you giggling.
[thunder rumbling]
It was perfect.
[kisses]
Good night.
[wind howls]
[creaking]
[wind howling]
[locks door]
- [gasping]
- [Rose] Mom. wake up!
[panting] What? What happened?
[pants] Ollie was right.
Someone's outside.
[creaking]
[Rose] See?
[breathes heavily]
[creaks]
[breathing shakily]
[Margaret] Wait here.
[Margaret grunting]
[creaking]
[creaks]
[clattering]
[footsteps approaching]
[whinnies]
[thrumming]
[villagers whispering]
[sheriff grunts]
[churchgoer 1] It's Jacob.
Esther's boy.
[sheriff] Cart must have gotten
overturned in the storm last night.
[villagers whispering]
Where's Esther?
I don't know.
I found Thomas
hiding under the cart alone.
so scared I could barely
get him to come out.
Probably left him there when
she went to go look for Jacob.
[villagers whispering]
- [villagers gasp]
- [gasps]
[breathing shakily]
- [coughs]
- [gasps]
[coughing]
[inhales sharply]
[Birdie] The Lord
works in mysterious ways.
[churchgoer 1 speaks indistinctly]
[Birdie] But he's a wise provider.
[sniffles]
All you can do is hold faith.
Faith that He has a plan for Jacob.
A plan more important
than we may ever understand.
I guess some things...
[sniffles]...are just out of our hands.
Some things aren't.
You can't just have faith
that He'll do something.
that it's part of the plan or they'll die.
We'll all be buried.
Sounds like pride to me.
Better than burying another child.
I tried to leave.
In a storm.
[Esther]
I can't change the weather. Margaret.
I can't make it rain.
[cries] What should I do?
You might try sweeping.
[Thomas coughing]
[continues coughing]
[breathes deeply]
Fit as a couple of fiddles.
It just started bleeding.
It wouldn't stop.
Well. air is dry.
That'd be my guess.
Your guess?
[sighs]
After Ollie and Ada. I just...
I worry.
Ada used to have
nosebleeds just like this.
Hmm.
Esther mentioned something
about the dust making Thomas ill.
The air.
[Dr. Cox exhales]
I got some masks for sale.
Might help.
[sighs]
You're taking your sleeping aid?
Mm-hmm.
[Dr. Cox] Well. you want my advice?
I say keep the house sealed
best you can. wear the masks.
Relax.
[wind howling]
[Rose] Mom. are you awake?
We're not even supposed to
sleep in the same room as you.
[Margaret] There was only enough fabric
to seal one room.
What if it happens again?
What if you stop sleeping?
Don't you understand that
the dust seeps through every opening?
That's why your cousin. Thomas. is sick
and it's why your nose is bleeding.
Well. I want to leave.
I want to go to Dad.
Well. when your father sends more money.
we'll take the next train.
I promise.
[Margaret] Has anyone had any mail?
We're going to try to leave
when Henry's next letter arrives.
Well. I guess you hadn't heard.
Service has been halted indefinitely.
Dust built up so much. a train in Woodward
skipped plumb off the tracks.
Killed every soul on board except for
one donkey in the freight car.
[chuckles]
You're stuck with us. looks like.
I see.
[Rose. Ollie laughing]
[sighs]
Any word on that drifter?
Well. now they're wondering
if the daddy did it himself.
Killed those kids and made up
the intruder wholesale.
Our neighbor said he'd been
acting off right before.
like a different man entirely.
Think about it.
No one saw that drifter coming or going.
Put your nightgown on. sweetheart.
[rustling]
[pants]
[door opens]
- Didn't I ask you to tie the doors?
- I did.
[Margaret] That cow is keeping us alive.
She's already starving
and something could have gotten to her.
- She could have died.
- [Rose] I tied it.
Well. then it has to be tighter. What?
[Margaret] Stop.
No more Grey Man. understand?
You need to finish your chores.
[sighs]
Rose.
Toss down some hay. would you?
[scoffs]
I'm sorry we argued. but...
[gasps]
[panting]
Rose!
In the barn. who did you see?
[panting]
But I thought you said he wasn't real.
That doesn't mean no one's out th...
[breathing heavily]
Stay.
[Margaret breathing heavily]
Come out or I will burn this whole thing
to the ground. I swear to God.
[breathing heavily]
[gasps]
[breathes heavily]
I told you to stay downstairs.
[Rose] We're scared.
[wood creaking]
[Rose gasps]
[gasps]
Stay back. girls.
[breathing heavily]
Who are you?
Name's Brother Wallace Grady.
I mean you no harm. ma'am.
Just needed shelter.
Henry told me y'all had this barn.
Henry? [breathes shakily]
Don't you recognize his jacket?
[sighs]
Did you hurt him?
Of course not. ma'am.
I'm a man of the cloth.
I. uh. stopped through the works detail
on my way west
and. Brother Henry. he give me this.
and he asked me to check in on y'all.
Why not just knock on the door?
That was my intention. ma'am.
soon as I had a chance to recover.
See. I got caught in that storm
on account of my bad leg.
Thought I looked too poorly.
I didn't want to scare your girls.
uh. scare you.
Rose. right?
And you're Margaret.
Henry would have told me.
The mail is slow going
with the trains out.
[panting] You have to go. Now.
I could earn my keep.
People need the Word of God these days.
- People need rain.
- [Wallace] One follows the other. ma'am.
Just get out! Out!
It's just your cow's starving.
which means you're about to be.
Right?
[Rose breathing shakily]
[Wallace] The milk's dried up.
I could get her producing again.
[Rose gasps]
- Okay. It's okay. it's okay.
- Oh. darlin'.
- [breathes shakily. spits]
- [Margaret] You're okay.
[Rose] Mom. help.
- [breathes heavily]
- Breathe. Breathe.
Stay back.
- Ma'am. I can help...
- [Rose breathes heavily] Mom.
...but I'd have to touch her.
Why?
- I lay hands.
- [Rose breathes heavily]
I can heal. Truly.
Even if you don't believe.
what could it hurt?
Margaret.
[Rose breathes heavily]
[coughs]
- [whimpers. breathing heavily]
- [speaks indistinctly]
[Rose groaning]
[muffled] Mom. help!
- [groaning]
- Let her go.
Let her go!
- [Wallace grunts]
- [Rose cries]
- [Wallace groaning]
- [Margaret] What did you do to her?
[panting]
Mom.
It stopped.
[breathes heavily]
[Wallace] I'll go. I'll go.
I just gotta rest.
[exhales deeply]
You said you could get our cow producing.
How?
[pants]
Tumbleweeds will soak this water right up.
Yield a lot of feed.
I sleep with this.
and I know how to use it.
Do you understand?
[sighs]
People will talk if I let you stay.
I could keep out of sight for a bit.
Stick to the barn.
[Rose] Did he heal me?
I don't know.
- [thunder rumbling]
- [gasps. panting]
[gasps] Rose!
[thunder rumbling]
[Birdie] Well. I hate you. Margaret.
What a fine hand you have.
Oh. [chuckles]
It's just our dream for the house.
Missed you in church this week. Margaret.
We were worried about you.
[Rose] Mom. it's Thomas.
[Thomas coughing]
[churchgoers chatter]
[Margaret] Where's Esther?
How did he get here by himself?
[Birdie] Oh. poor thing.
- Birdie. go fetch the sheriff.
- [Thomas coughing]
[Birdie] This is heartbreaking.
[sheriff]
She's not looking after him. Margaret.
Maybe find out if it's
a short-term grief kind of aberration
or something more serious.
[flies buzzing]
Esther. It's Margaret.
Esther?
[Esther breathing heavily]
[Margaret] Remember when Ada passed?
For a long while.
I thought I might just join her.
But you have to think of your other child.
His health.
The man has... been looking after him.
Or was that a dream?
[flies buzzing]
Have some water.
Just a sip.
How long have you been lying here?
[coughing]
She... She's not fit. [cries]
You sure?
I'd take him.
but we can't feed him. [sniffs]
Come with me. little Thomas.
[grunts] Yeah.
- [Esther] Margaret. [cries]
- [sighs]
[sighs] Thank you.
Thank you for visiting me.
[cries]
[Margaret] It's all right.
You just have to take care of yourself.
[sighs] What's going on?
[sheriff] Just for a little while. Esther.
What's for a little while?
Just until you get back on your feet.
Are you taking him? Where you taking him?
[sheriff] I won't... Oh. Hey.
Let's just take a moment here.
[cries]
[Esther]
He's my son. He's all I've got left.
You're no different than me.
you know. You know that?
You always thought you were.
You'll be just like me. you hear me?
I'll show you what it's like.
Look at me. You'll be just like me.
You see me?
You'll be just like me.
You'll see. You'll be sorry.
Don't take him from me.
[Wallace] "Count it all joy
when you fall into various trials.
knowing that the testing of your faith
produces patience."
It's lovely.
Yours?
It was my mother's.
[Margaret] Hmm.
Is she how you got into the church?
Partly.
My daddy was a preacher.
He told me I had the touch young.
All my siblings do. I have four sisters.
Where are they now?
[sighs] Two are in Texas
and. uh. scarlet fever took the others
while I was off spreading the Word.
Ollie had it. Scarlet fever. And Ada.
When they went into quarantine.
Ada never stopped calling out for me.
I clawed the door separating us until
my nails were ripped away from the quick.
Temporary parting is a burden
of our earthly lives.
But there's a reunion
that lasts an eternity.
You believe that?
I have to.
Don't have a choice.
[Rose laughing]
Those girls are lucky to have you.
You don't think that?
After Ada. my sleep was fitful.
And I... [softly] I'd do things.
No mail today. But the letter carrier said
a haze is dropping in.
[Wallace] God above. I thank you.
I thank you for the warmth
of the Bellum family.
You connected us through Brother Henry.
and for that. I am eternally grateful.
Thank you for Rose's continued health.
and we ask that you hold little Ollie
in your ever-loving light.
I'm reminded of a verse
that my father taught me.
"Neither this man nor his parents sinned.
but this happened so that the works of God
might be displayed in Him."
Thank you for this nourishment.
And thank you for this.
[Margaret] This came today?
- Ooh. is that from Daddy?
- [Rose] Mm-hmm.
- Mm-mmm. Next one. little...
- [Wallace] What's he got to say?
Stop!
- [Margaret] Rose.
- Well. I...
Hey.
[clears throat. chuckles]
[chuckles]
"Dear girls.
my first hope is that
you can... d... deci... "[mutters]
[Margaret] Decipher.
- [Rose] Decipher.
- [Margaret] Mm-hmm.
- "Decipher my chicken scratch."
- [Margaret chuckles]
"My second hope is that these
blades of grass will still be green
- by the time they reach you."
- [Margaret] Mmm.
[Rose] "Just know that when I picked them.
they were the brightest thing
you ever saw." [chuckles]
"This next bit's just for Mama. girls."
[Margaret] Oh.
Come on. [chuckles]
Y'all telling secrets over there?
Now. Rose.
Put her down.
[Wallace] That seems like a bad idea.
Who are you?
Rose. read the letter. Aloud.
[stammers] "I'm fine. Margaret.
but my jacket was took.
Along with the letter in its pocket.
money. and sweets for the girls.
There was a preacher hanging about.
asked to stay the night.
Next day. my bunkmate didn't
come back from lunch.
Found him with his head cracked open
like an egg. boots pulled off his feet.
Nobody knows how the preacher made off.
Like he just vanished."
I wouldn't have hurt y'all.
[Rose whimpers]
- Where's the money?
- [Wallace] Gone.
Where's yours?
Gone. Let her go.
I will. In exchange for that letter.
We better hold on to it.
[breathes shakily]
See what the sheriff thinks.
[gunshot]
[crashes]
Y'all would've starved without me.
Without you. his first letter
would have gotten to us.
We could have left!
[Wallace] "Do not neglect
to show hospitality to strangers.
for thereby some have
entertained angels. unaware."
- Angels.
- [Wallace] I fixed her. didn't I?
How about I undo it?
Put her back the way she was.
[breathes heavily]
Fixed her? You're a con.
Your father. the preacher. a con too?
My father. he'd like you.
Get out.
Get out!
[Wallace] I'd be scared too.
You're out here all alone.
Don't know when a man could come by.
A few locks. Some twine?
That's not gonna stop me. [chuckles]
That's not gonna stop the Grey Man.
[glass shatters]
I'll be seeing y'all.
[Ollie breathes shakily]
[Margaret breathing shakily]
[door creaks]
[creaking continues]
[huffs. moos]
[Ollie whispers] Mommy.
[Margaret] Ollie.
Did you say that?
[gasps]
What are you doing. Esther?
You'll be just like me.
You'll see. You'll breathe him in. He'll
make you do [distorted] terrible things.
[screaming]
Mama. Mama. Mama.
[whimpers]
Were you outside all night?
[wind whistling]
[furniture dragging]
[wood creaking]
- [Wallace] Margaret.
- [gasps]
It's not gonna stop.
[door slams]
- [pounding on door]
- [Rose] Mom! Get us out!
[sobbing] Mom! Mommy! Mom!
- [sobbing. screaming]
- Open the door! Unlock it. please!
- [Rose] Mom! [sobbing]
- Is he in there?
- [Rose] Get us out!
- [panting]
Mommy! [sobbing]
[Margaret] Get out of here! Go!
[sizzling]
[panting]
[Rose] Did you knock the lamp over?
[Margaret] No. it's Wallace.
How's he doing it?
I was up the whole night.
And the doors are still locked.
Unless he doesn't have to use doors.
Mom. what do you mean?
[breathes heavily]
I should have sealed under this door.
Mom. But the... the Grey Man's
just a story. like... like you said.
I-I lent Wallace the book one day.
But he healed you.
right?
And he came into a locked house
while I stood watch.
[knocks on door]
[shushing]
[whispering] That is what he wants.
Go get your sister.
Slide fabric under the door
and don't come out.
[unlocks door]
Hi.
[Margaret] You're looking well.
What are you doing here?
I've come to apologize. Margaret.
The things that I was thinking and...
[sighs]...the things I said. I'm sorry.
We're family.
Can't we put this all behind us
and just start fresh? I miss you.
I miss the girls and...
Well. you know...
folks are starting to worry.
They haven't seen you in a while.
It's difficult with such low light.
[sighs]
It's much easier to breathe though.
[creaking]
[wind whistling]
I wonder if it might help to get out more.
It's wild what happens upstairs
when you're allowed to stew. [chuckles]
It might be good to take the lid off
and let some of that steam out.
You know.
I've been trying to get out more too.
I've been working with the preacher.
praying to get my head right.
I've been visiting Thomas...
[knocking]
[wind whistling]
Margaret?
You might could start
with the dance tonight.
Take it from me. you don't want people
speculating the way they have been.
You might want to show 'em you're okay.
Oh. you're right.
We really should get out more. [chuckles]
[Esther] Yeah.
[purring]
[Rose] We're really going to the dance?
Esther said
people were worried about us. so...
We have to put on a good face and go.
Well. Sheriff Bell will be there.
We could tell him about Wallace.
what's been happening.
Without the letter from your father...
If the sheriff thought
something was wrong. or...
[voice cracking] He could take you both.
Promise me you won't mention it.
[chuckles] It's so pretty.
Oh. [chuckles] I think it's the wearer.
[chuckles]
Stay inside!
[Ollie. Rose laughing]
[sighs]
We're very well. [chuckles] You?
[laughing continues]
- [Rose gasps. coughs]
- [body thuds]
- Rose!
- [coughing continues]
[Rose] I can't breathe! [panting]
- [grunts]
- [screams] Mom!
Mommy! Mom. stop!
What is wrong with you?
[breathes shakily]
You were crying out!
You were choking! You couldn't breathe!
No. I was laughing!
[wind whistling]
It's ruined.
[sighs]
I don't think we should still go.
You'll still look perfect.
It's not just the dress.
What are you...
Stop!
It's all right. Rose.
Daddy will be home soon.
and we'll sort everything out.
Until then. I just need to go
and show everyone we're okay.
[♪ band playing
"Oh. My Darling. Clementine"]
[attendants chattering. laughing]
[whispering]
Y'all look right as rain. Margaret.
- We're feeling much better. Thank you.
- [Birdie] Hmm. Mm-hmm.
Excuse me.
- [Rose] Yeah. that's right.
- Margaret!
Would you. uh. care to go for a spin?
Happy to.
[♪ band playing
"She'll Be Coming 'Round the Mountain"]
So. how's things?
Oh. we had a little bug.
but we're feeling much better.
[Sheriff Bell] Glad to hear it.
Have you been getting enough rest lately?
Why?
What did Rose say?
What do you mean?
Oh. nothing.
She... She's been having nightmares lately.
Oh.
[attendants whispering]
- Margaret.
- What?
[stammers] You. uh...
[music stops]
You...
Oh. goodness.
It's just a cut. [chuckles]
It's just my leg.
Please keep playing.
Sorry. Pardon me.
[door opens]
[Margaret gasps]
What are you doing with him?
[chuckles] With Reverend Shaw?
Excuse me.
I didn't want the girls to miss the dance.
but this cut
h-has me a little light-headed.
[Esther] Margaret.
Why don't I stop by later
with that healer that I mentioned?
Healer?
[Esther] Yeah.
You mean Wallace.
No.
His name is Everett Lee.
He's real nice.
He got me thinking right again and...
He even helps me keep up the house
and he got me this. [chuckles]
I don't care what he's calling himself.
That is the man who was
hiding in our loft. Sheriff.
Who threatened us!
[Esther] Margaret.
that can't be. [chuckles]
[Margaret] You are housing a murderer.
Henry sent me a letter.
Your healer killed a man at his ca...
No. she... she's telling the truth.
I saw him too.
And... And he threatened to come back.
You see?
He's not of this world.
He's...
He's been sneaking into our house.
moving things at night.
trying to hurt the girls.
He can get through locks. closed windows.
He comes apart like dust.
- He seeps in through the cracks.
- Mom. please. Please. come on.
You can breathe him in.
He'll make you do terrible things.
- [chattering]
- [door opens]
They're gossiping right about now.
Wondering if I'm...
If I...
But I said I saw him too.
It doesn't matter.
They saw me like this.
[gasps] Mom?
- Mom.
- [gasps]
[whimpers]
Who did that?
You did.
When? [gasps]
[scissors snipping]
Was he in me?
It's okay.
- [pounding on door]
- [Margaret gasps]
[doorknob rattles]
Wait. wait.
You heard that. right?
[Rose] Yes.
But what if it's someone checking on us?
Put your masks on. Slide fabric
under the door the moment I leave.
[breathing shakily]
[Wallace whispers] Margaret.
[Margaret] Wallace!
- [Esther whispers] Margaret.
- [panting]
[Wallace] Here. Margaret.
[Esther whispers] Margaret.
[Wallace whispers] Here. Margaret.
You'll be just like me.
[Esther] You'll be just like me.
Margaret.
- [Wallace] Here. Margaret.
- [Esther] Margaret.
[Wallace] People are talking.
[Wallace. Esther] Behind you.
[Rose] Mom!
What happened? Was it Wallace?
Yes. but he vanished!
[Rose] What do you mean?
Like the book!
He's in the air. Rose!
He could be anywhere!
Get inside! Now!
[whimpers]
[panting]
[door creaks]
[Rose] Mom?
Wallace?
[breathes shakily]
[footsteps]
- [wood creaks]
- [gasps]
[Margaret] Ada. I'm sorry. [whimpering]
I'm sorry.
Please. let me in.
Please.
- Mom? [screams]
- I'm sorry.
I'm so sorry.
[whimpers. breathes shakily]
[door opens. closes]
[breathing shakily]
[Rose] Mom? [breathing shakily]
[Wallace] You're asleep.
It's you.
You're sleepwalking again.
It's me.
It's Rose.
[breathes shakily]
Mom. it's me! Wake up.
- [Wallace] Don't shoot. it's Rose!
- [Rose] Don't shoot. it's Rose!
- It's your daughter!
Don't shoot.
- [Wallace] Put the gun down.
- [Rose] Put the gun down.
[Rose sobs]
- [Wallace] Mommy. I'm really scared.
- [Rose] Mommy. I'm really scared.
- You have to trust me!
- You have to wake up!
You're not Rose.
Mom.
Mama. Mama. Mama. Mama!
- Mama! Ma...
- Mama!
[sobbing]
[breathing shakily]
Rose. what are you doing out here?
[sobs] The Grey Man isn't haunting us.
What are you talking about?
It's you.
[inhales sharply] You're
doing things in your sleep again.
That's how the chairs moved
and how the bed caught fire.
You can never say that again
about the sleepwalking.
Not to anyone.
[sobs]
Mom. why are you doing this?
Why?
To protect you.
[sobs] Then we should have left.
- I was trying to keep us all together.
- [sobs] Mom.
You. me.
and your sisters.
Ada is dead! [gasps]
Don't you understand?
You girls are me.
Parts of me.
- Cutaway pieces that never heal.
- Mom. you're scaring me.
I bleed when you're hurt.
- I'm alive in that grave...
- [sobbing]
...suffocating under
the dirt with your sister.
And I would do anything.
anything to keep us together.
to keep us whole.
[whimpers. grunts]
[pants. gasping]
- [Margaret] Rose!
- [pounding on door]
[panting]
[door creaking]
Ollie!
[grunts]
[Rose grunting]
[gasps] Aunt Esther?
[gasping. sobbing]
- [wind rumbles]
- [weather vane squeaks]
[Margaret] It's too late!
There's nowhere to go. Rose!
Let her go!
Mom!
[sobbing]
[pants] That wasn't Wallace.
You killed Aunt Esther.
[Margaret] You're hurting her. Rose!
- [Rose] Let her go!
- [knocking]
Help!
[grunting]
- [screaming. grunting]
- [knocking]
[Margaret] They will take you.
They will take you away. Please.
[Margaret panting. grunting]
[knocking]
[Rose panting. distorted]
[Margaret shushes. distorted]
Hi. sweet pea.
Where's Mama?
[breathing heavily]
[whimpers. breathes shakily]
Rose. you all right?
She's not fit.
Rose.
All right now.
You two just go wait in there.
Don't worry.
We're just gonna have
a nice little chat. all right?
I don't know what's gotten into her.
[inhales deeply]
For the coyotes.
Had one recently?
They're always around.
Did. uh. did...
did Esther come by. Margaret?
- She-She said she was gonna check in.
- [wood banging]
I hope she wasn't lost in the storm.
Margaret. the-the girls seem rattled.
Stir crazy. I guess.
Maybe I ought to take 'em.
Just till Henry gets back.
- Hey. now. hey.
- [sobbing]
Hey. hey. hey. hey. hey.
Hey. hey. hey.
Margaret. it's just a few days now.
just a few days.
You done good. You done real good.
[shushes]
[grunts. breathes heavily]
[grunts. gasps]
[grunts]
[breathes heavily]
[grunting]
[panting]
[groaning]
[gasps]
[breathes shakily]
They're going to hang me. Rose.
But there is a way around it.
a way to stay together.
A reunion that lasts an eternity.
We just go to sleep like any other night.
but longer.
Please. no.
Yes. baby.
- It's the only way.
- [sobbing]
It's okay to be scared.
It's okay. Come here.
Come here.
[sobbing]
Oh.
I'm sorry.
I'm so sorry for everything. Rose.
You're the loves of my life.
you know that.
[kisses]
[sobs]
[sobbing]
I'm just so tired. Mommy.
Let's go be with Ada. All right?
[sobbing]
[knife clatters]
Can you tell us about the wheat first?
Yes.
Our first year. it just took hold.
The field was-was chest-high.
And when the wind blew. the wheat
would ripple and wave like the ocean.
And we'd play in that field for hours.
[inhales sharply]
All together.
Could we have the medicine
in some peaches?
I think that's a wonderful idea.
[Rose] Ollie!
[Rose] Mom!
I-I tried to stop her.
but Ollie got scared and ran out.
[breathes shakily] She has to be with us.
She could be drowning!
[breathes heavily]
[Margaret gasps] Oh. please!
Where is she?
[choking]
[breathes heavily]
[no audible dialogue]
[mouthing] I'm sorry.
[coughing. gasping]
[coughing. choking]
[children laughing]
[breathes heavily. gasps]
[train wheels clacking]